Music is the strongest form of magic
Alive Inside is a documentary film directed by Michael Rossato-Bennett.
Five million Americans suffer from Alzheimer's disease and
dementia—many of them alone in nursing homes.
A man with a simple idea discovers that songs embedded deep in
memory can ease pain and awaken these fading minds.
Joy and life are resuscitated, and our cultural fears over aging are confronted.
Alive Inside: A Story of Music and Memory is a 2014 American documentary
film directed and produced by Michael Rossato-Bennett.
The film premiered in the competition category of U.S.
Documentary Competition program at the 2014 Sundance
Film Festival on January 18, 2014.
It won the Audience Award: U.S.
Documentary at the festival.
The documentary explores diseases that impair neurological function, such as Alzheimer's disease and
dementia, and proposes a treatment option that is claimed to improve a patient's quality of life.
It discusses that the elderly community are on the decline in social status
and that western society neglects old age to idealize youth.
It includes a series of interviews with individuals
on neurology, geriatrics, and music.
The documentary tells the story of patients and their experience with music and creating personalized playlists
for elderly patients with dementia and Alzheimer's disease based on their music preferences.
The film explores themes of dementia, alzheimer's
disease, health, ageism mental  health.
The tone is thought_provoking.